### **ABOUT ME**

I am passionate and experienced in fisheries and biological science. My strengths include critical system thinking and applied quantitative analysis that are of significant value to my problem–solving ability. I am eagerly interested in a research-based opportunity that would encourage my professional growth.

### **EXPERTISE**

- Fisheries management
- Fish population dynamics and stock assessment modeling
- · Aquatic resource management

### **SKILLS**

- Critical system thinking, independent learning, and problem-solving skills
- Interpersonal and communication skills
- Computer literacy
- Design of experiments, data collection, and management
- · Data analysis and presentation

### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

R  $\blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare$  (proficient)

Python  $\blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare \blacksquare$  (comfortable)

C++  $\blacksquare \blacksquare$  (basic)

# **EDUCATION**

University of Tasmania

Master of Applied-Science in Marine Environment with Honours, First-class honours June 2016 – December 2018

Nha Trang University

Bachelor of Biotechnology September 2002 – January 2007

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

<u>Vietnam Centre of Science and Technology for</u> Sea Culture

Research scientist

June - December 2019

 My research concentrated on environmental issues associated with marine farming operations, the promotion of sustainable aquaculture in Vietnam.

Riawunna Centre for Aboriginal Education, University of Tasmania

Casual academic tutor

March - December 2017

Responsibilities include:

 I provided one-on-one tutoring for Aboriginal students. Courses include: Responsible fishing practices (JFA535), and Fisheries management (JFA542).

http://www.utas.edu.au/riawunna

# Southeast Asian Fisheries Development Centre

Member of Regional Fisheries Policy Network

February 2014 - December 2014

Responsibilities include:

- identifying issues concerning fisheries administration;
- conducting studies, trainings, consultations in accordance with agreed fisheries policies among member countries;
- promoting regional cooperation for strengthening human resources.

http://www.seafdec.org

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

 Awarded Member of Golden Key International Honour Society by UTAS Chapter

https://www.goldenkey.org/

 Awarded Australian Awards Scholarships (AAS) issued by The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade of Australia in July 2015

https://dfat.gov.au/people-to-people/australia-awards/Pages/australia-awards-scholarships.aspx

 Awarded KOICA Scholarship granted by the Korea International Cooperation Agency in March 2015

http://www.koica.go.kr/english/schemes/ciat/index.html

### **CERTIFICATES**

Elements of Shipboard Safety (ESS)

### **VOLUNTEERING**

- Volunteer at Tamar Island Wetland Reserve Centre, Tasmania, Australia, December 2018.
- Volunteer at Barneys English café, Launceston, Tasmania, Australia, from January 2017 to December 2018.
- Member of Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative Network (YSEALI), Hanoi, Vietnam, in 2015.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Directorate of Fisheries of Vietnam

Fisheries official

Oct 2012 – Dec 2013/ Jan 2015 – May 2016 Responsibilities include:

- consulting with authorized levels in developing Vietnamese fisheries policies;
- conducting studies, trainings, and consultations that aim to improve data collection;
- · monitoring registered VMS vessels.

## Institute of Fisheries Economics & Planning

Researcher

January 2010 - October 2012

 My research's theme was centred on the use of applied GIS techniques in fish farming management (species: Acipenser baerii, Oncorhynchus mykiss), and assessing the vulnerabilities of Vietnamese rural provinces to climate change.

# Institute of Marine Environment and Resources

Junior researcher

March 2008 - December 2009

 My research interest focused on benthic invertebrates, coral ecosystem, and IUU fishing in Vietnam.

### **REFERENCE**

Dr. Jawahar Patil

Adjunct Lecturer at Institute of Marine and Antarctic Studies, University of Tasmania jawahar.patil@utas.edu.au

Dr. Justin Bell

Senior Research Scientist at Victorian Fisheries Authority bbeellyy@gmail.com

### **Publication**

Quemper F, Dam TD, Nguyen LM, Nguyen ATM, Nguyen H, Vu HM (2020) Utilization of the light density to reduce the development of Lyngbya sp. and their growth on Caulerpa lentillifera J. Agardh in a recirculating aquaculture system Vietnam journal of marine science and technology 20 doi: https://doi.org/10.15625/1859-3097/20/3/1488 /http://www.vjs.ac.vn/index.php/jmst/article/view/14880